♪〜
〜♪
（吹き荒れる砂嵐の音）
（ドアの開閉音）
You sure you want out here?
It's 500 yarz to town.
（運転手）
本当に ここでいいのか？
町まで500ヤーズはあるぞ
Thanks for the lift.
（ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード）
助かったよ
You aren't going to listen, are you?
聞く男(タマ)じゃなさそうだな
こりゃあ
Sandstorms are forming
4,000 yarz around the Orleans area.
（ラジオの音声）オリンズ地方の
周囲4000ヤーズに—
砂嵐が発生中
All transportation has been stopped
with no sign of resumption.
すべての交通機関は
運行を停止しており—
再開のめどは
立っておりません
There's nothing we can do.
（メリル･ストライフ）
どうにもなりませんわね
There, there.
Think of it as a vacation!
（ミリィ･トンプソン）
まあまあ
たまの休暇だと思って
楽しみましょう
If this was a vacation,
I'd spend it someplace quieter.
それなら
もう少し落ちついた場所で—
過ごしたかったですわ
I did it!
（ステファニー）やったー！
- Not again!
- I did it, I did it!
（客たち）またかよ
やった やった！
クラブのストレートよ
An all-club straight!
（執事）
すばらしいです お嬢様
- That's wonderful, miss!
- Now I'm getting into it!
ノってきた ノってきた
I can't play like this.
（客Ａ）やってられねえぜ
ええ？
もうやめちゃうの？
What? You're giving up already?
I was just getting started!
ここからが
いいところなのに
I wish I never started at all.
（客Ａ）
俺にとっちゃ 最悪の時間だ
（ステファニー）あ…
（メリル）あ？
Would you like to play?
どう 入らない？
Are you playing Old Maid?
（ミリィ）ババ抜きですか？
She doesn't know any other game,
so no, thanks.
この程度の知識しか
ありませんから—
結構ですわ
そう言わないで ねえ？
Don't be that way, please?
I'll play.
（イングウェイ）
俺が入ろう
えっ やったあ！
All right! Let's begin
before my luck changes!
ツキが変わらないうちに
早くやりましょう
On one condition.
（イングウェイ）ただし
はあっ！
We're playing for your life.
賭けるのは—
あんたの命だ
There are three things
I can't tolerate in this world.
（スタン）世の中には
許せねえものが３つある
People who put ice in alcohol, the
pattern on the silhouette scorpion...
酒に氷を入れること
面影サソリの模様
そして平穏のありがたみを
知らねえやからだ
...and slime who don't
appreciate tranquillity.
A robbery in my jurisdiction?!
俺の所轄内で強盗事件(たたき)だと！
Not on my watch!
ふざけやがって
（車のブレーキ音）
What's the situation?
（ボストーク伯爵）
じょ… 状況は どうなってる？
Dick! Inform the earl.
ディック！
伯爵様に お伝えしろ
（ディック）はい
Yessir.
From the testimony
of the witnesses...
目撃者の証言を総合したところ—
...the criminal group totals 4,
who have taken a total of 4 hostages.
犯人グループは４人
人質も４人です
Everyone who got away says
that a girl who loves cards...
カード好きのお嬢さんが
その中に含まれていることは—
逃げてきた全員の口から
聞けましたよ
...is among the hostages,
Mr. Bostalk.
ボストーク伯爵
What are their demands?
犯人の要求は？
They want $ $ 10,000,000
in nonconsecutive $ $ 100 bills...
番号不ぞろいの
100ダブドル紙幣を１千万分と—
...and a getaway wagon.
逃走用のワゴン車です
Did they commit this crime
knowing she's my daughter?!
私の娘がいることを
知っての犯行か？
でしょうな
Probably. You're the only
one in this town capable...
この町で
１千万ダブドルなんて大金を—
...of getting $ $ 10,000,000
together in short order.
即日で用意できるのは
あなただけですよ
They won't get away with this!
甘い顔は見せられんぞ
If word of this gets around,
hooligans will come swarming!
うわさが広まれば
ごろつきどもが—
この町に集まってくる
娘は慰み者にされ
砂漠に捨てられるのがオチだ
They'll use her as a plaything
and leave her to die in the desert!
You speak with the wisdom
of past experience...
（スタン）昔日(せきじつ)の経験が
ものを言いますな
..."Grim Reaper" Bostalk.
死神ボストーク
黙れ！ スタン
Shut up, Stan! If you're
the law in this town...
この町の保安官なら娘を無事—
...concentrate on the
safe rescue of my daughter!
助け出すことだけを考えればいい
他人が何人死のうと問題じゃない
I don't care how many have to die!
Don't confuse what's important!
大切なことを はき違えるな
おおっ
Never order me around.
This isn't the old days.
俺に命令するんじゃねえ
昔とは違うんだよ
（ボストーク）くっ…
（スタン）フン
（ディック）フッ
（イヤホンから漏れる音楽）
（ヴァッシュ）ズッチャカ…
（ディック）お…
（ヴァッシュ）
ズッチャカ ズッチャカ…
おっ おい…
Hey.
（ヴァッシュ）
ズッチャカ ズッチャカ
- Who is that?
- Beats me.
誰だ！ あれは
知りませんよ
Look out!
Get back here, you idiot!
危ねえぞ
戻れ バカ野郎
We have criminals
trapped in that bar!!
その店には
犯罪者が籠城中だ！
（ヴァッシュ）
タオッ！ ズッチャカ
He's too busy dancing to notice.
踊りに夢中で
気付いてないみたいですね
クソッタレが
That crazy boob!
He'll excite the criminals!
犯人を刺激しちまうぞ
（ガラスが割れる音）
（３人）おっ
（ヴァッシュのハミング）
（銃声）
（スタン）撃たれやがった
They've opened fire!
（銃声）
（スタン）あ？
He's dodging.
（ディック）避けてます
No, he's too busy
dancing to notice.
（スタン）いや
踊りに夢中で気付いてねえんだ
I think he'll make it inside.
（ディック）このままじゃ
入っちゃいますね
（銃声）
（ボストーク）やめろ！
Stop it!
やめろ！
やめろー！
STOP IT!
（マーヴィン）
何者(もん)だ おめえは
Who the hell are you?
- Are you suicidal?
- Or just an idiot?
（ジーン）命知らずか？
（デニム）
それとも ただのバカか？
（メリルたち）ああ…
（風船ガムが割れる音）
うわああ 強盗だ！
誰か助けてえ！
Robbers! Somebody help me!!
Help! I never knew what hit me!
助けてえ！
- He's just an idiot.
Help! I never knew what hit me!
（マーヴィン）
ただのバカのほうでしたね
No mere idiot
would scream like that.
（イングウェイ）
ただどころの騒ぎか あれが
Help me! Help meee!
（ヴァッシュ）
ヘルプミー ヘルプミー！
Make that 5 hostages.
これで人質は５名っと
The plan hasn't changed.
作戦は変えんぞ
It just means there's
one more life on the line.
不幸な仏が１人増える
可能性ができただけだ
How goes it?
手はずは どうなってる？
２時間ほど前に
連絡がつきました
We got through 2 hours ago.
They will be here by the
deadline the criminals gave us.
犯人側から指定された時刻には
間に合います
Earl, you keep praying
for your daughter's safety.
伯爵　それまでお嬢さんの無事を
祈っててやってください
Oh, yes,
and don't forget the money.
ああ それとカネの用意も
忘れずに頼みますよ
（ボストーク）むむっ
（殴る音）
Ow! Be more gentle, brother!
あ… 痛(いて)てて
もう少し優しくしてよ ブラザー
I won't try anything!
Here, take my gun!
何もしないよ ほら
拳銃 ほらほら〜
（デニム）ん？ なんだこりゃ？
What's this?
Hey!
おい！
This is heavy!
（マーヴィン）おっ 重い
It's custom-made. You're packing
some serious firepower for a wimp.
（イングウェイ）特注かよ
腰抜けの割には
すげえ物 持ってやがんな
Give it back after, please!
あとで返してね プリーズ
You shut up!
（デニム）黙れよ お前は
（ヴァッシュ）あっ…
- H-Hello.
- Hello.
（ミリィ）ど… どうも
どうも〜
Life's been hard since I met you guys.
君たちと出会ってから
ひどい目ばっかり遭うな
That sentiment is all mine!
それは こっちのセリフですわ
痛(いて)え
Ow! I felt that.
今のは効いた
Are you okay?
（ステファニー）大丈夫？
（ヴァッシュ）おっ？
ふわああ〜
何？
What?
よいっしょ よいっしょ
よいっしょ
Hey!
ちょ ちょっと…
ちょっと やめてよ
Hey, stop that!
イヤーッ！
（蹴る音）
（ジーン）じっとしてろ
Stay still!
最低
Creep.
You people are horrible.
That is no way to treat a lady!
それにしても
ひどいな 君たちも
レディーの扱いは
そうじゃないだろ
We're ladies too, you know!
私たちも
レディーですわよ
Oh, yeah.
（ヴァッシュ）そういやそうか
（メリル）フン！
（ジーン）
フッ この女は特別だ
She's special.
She serves as a warning!
見せしめなんだよ
How do you mean?
どういうことですの？
They're probably
after my family's fortune!
きっと私の家の財産が
目当てなのよ
そうでなきゃ—
Why else would anyone
rob this two-bit bar?!
誰がこんな安酒場に
押し入るもんですか
Forgive me, miss.
I failed to protect you!
申し訳ございません お嬢様
私(わたくし)がついていながら
Depressing.
うわっ くらい
ふんっ あなたたち
You had better not demand
anything too extravagant!
あまり無茶な
要求しないほうがいいわ
Besides, if it's pocket money you want,
I can easily get that from Daddy!
それに お小遣い程度なら—
私がパパに
お願いしてあげるわよ
Pocket money?!
（デニム）お小遣いだと！
（ステファニー）キャーッ
（ジーン）チ… チクショウ
Dammit, I'll kill her right now!
この女 今すぐ殺してやる！
Knock it off, Jean!
やめろ ジーン
（ステファニー）うわあ…
- Miss!
- Stop!
（執事）お嬢様！
（メリル）おやめなさい
I'll pull the trigger, I swear!
Cry! Scream, damn you!
（ジーン）オラ 引くぞ
オラ 泣け　わめけ
チクショウ！
（ステファニー）あ…
（ジーン）ぐぐっ…
（ジーン）あっ…
ハア ハア…
Calm down! Calm down, Jean.
落ち着け いいか
落ち着くんだ ジーン
（３人）ハア…
You keep your mouth shut,
'cause the next time it might be me.
（イングウェイ）
貴様 もうしゃべるな
次は俺が殺(や)るかもしれんぞ
Let's keep this peaceful, okay?
平和にいきましょうよ 平和に
This was your doing!
（デニム）お前の仕業か
You freaked the living crap
out of me!
（マーヴィン）
ビックリするじゃねえか
この野郎
I'm sorry,
I'm sorry!
（ヴァッシュ）
ご… ごめんなさい
ごめんなさい
Gum?
ガム？
You're kidding!
まさか…
ぐわあああ…
Couldn't be.
（イングウェイ）まさかな
（荒くれ者たちの笑い声）
You're using them?
（ボストーク）
こいつらを使うのか？
Yes. They're a lovely bunch...
（スタン）ええ
彼らはカネのためなら
親兄弟だろうと—
...who would easily kill their
own family for a little money.
平然と殺してくれる
ステキな連中です
They're quite skillful,
and best of all...
腕は相応に立ちますし—
何より 彼らの命に対する
認識の軽さがいい
...is their lack of respect
for the lives of others.
They are the perfect men
to take control of the situation.
今回の事件を
収拾してくれるのに—
うってつけの精鋭ですよ
They won't accidentally shoot
my daughter as well, I trust?
娘まで間違って
撃ったりしないだろうな
That depends on what you offer them.
Unless there is money involved...
それは あなたの報酬しだいです
カネが懸かってなきゃ—
...they won't be able to tell
her apart from a sand roach.
連中 娘さんと砂ゴキブリの
区別もつきません
なっ？
Right?
ヒッヒヒヒ
Give them what they want,
but don't let them touch my daughter!
言い値でいい
ただし 絶対
娘に手を出させるな
You've got yourself a team.
契約成立ですな
Now let's get this party under way.
さて パーティーを
始めるとしましょうか
（ヴァッシュ）へ… ヘヘッ
- Get it through your head!
- Yessir.
（ジーン）少しは懲りろよ
（ヴァッシュ）はい
ハア…
（風車が回る音）
Shit!
（デニム）クソッ
（３人）ハッ
はあ〜 もうすぐ時間だぜ
カネと車は まだなのかよ
It's almost time!
Where's the wagon and the money?!
They'd better not
be playing for time!
まさか あいつら—
引き延ばしを
考えてんじゃねえだろうな
Save it for later, okay?
We've still got work to do.
（マーヴィン）
それぐらいで やめとけ
まだ仕事は残ってるんだ
Excuse me, but if you receive
the money, will you release her?
（執事）あの… お金を払えば—
お嬢様を解放して
いただけるんですよね？
Ask her father.
He might try something stupid.
（イングウェイ）
こいつの親父に聞くんだな
ヘタなことしたら分からねえぞ
（ジーン）
しっ！ 静かにしてくれ
Keep it down.
I'm trying to hear.
サテライトが
（ジーンの小声）
Vash the Stampede?!
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード！
（マーヴィン）ええ！
Yeah, The Humanoid Typhoon
is in this town.
（ジーン）あの
ヒューマノイド･タイフーンが—
この町に来てるらしい
お… おい
顔役のボストークか保安官に—
Hey, if big man Bostalk or the
sheriff hires him, we're toast!
雇われでもしたら事だぞ
He'll kill us all!
俺たちは皆殺しだ
Don't lose your head.
It's almost time.
まあ そう慌てることもねえ
もうすぐ時間じゃねえか
（ヴァッシュ）うわあ
向こうから何か来ますよ
Hey, hey! Something's coming!
Shut up! You stay still!!
（デニム）うるせえ！
てめえは じっとしてろ
Yessir.
（ヴァッシュ）はい
It's here! It's the wagon!
（デニム）来た！ ワゴン車だ
Stay still!!
じっとしてろ！
Here's your wagon and
$ $ 10,000,000 in nonconsecutive bills!
（スタン）
貴様たちが要求したワゴン車と—
番号不ぞろいの１千万ダブドル
We have met your demands!
Release your hostages immediately!
これで
すべてそろったはずだ
速やかに人質を解放しろ
Not yet! First we check the wagon
and the money! By the way...
まだだ　車とカネを調べる
言っておくが—
...try anything, and the hostages
are dead meat! Got that?!
何かしたら
人質の命は保障しねえ
いいな！
I'll go.
（マーヴィン）俺が行く
Be careful.
油断するな
Will your father hand over
the money without a fuss?
（メリル）
あなたのお父さんは—
黙って お金を
払ってくれますの？
Daddy will do anything for me.
（ステファニー）
私のためなら パパは
なんでもしてくれるわ
Stan is another matter.
でもスタンは…
（ヴァッシュ）ん？
（スタン）フンッ
（マーヴィン）あっ ああ…
It's a trap!
ワナだー！
（銃声）
マーヴィン
- Marvin!
- That bastard!!
（ジーン）あの野郎！
Idiot! Come back here, Jean!
（イングウェイ）
バカ 戻れ ジーン
（ジーン）ああ…
ぐわっ　ぐぐっ…
ジーン！
Jean!
（デニム）だああっ
（メリルとミリィ）うわああ
（荒くれ者たち）
ヒャハッハッハッ
（発砲音）
（メリルとミリィ）ヒエーッ
（荒くれ者の笑い声と発砲音）
（ステファニー）キャアーッ
（黒猫の鳴き声）
- You okay?
- I think so!
（ヴァッシュ）大丈夫？
ええ
Is this how they do
things in this town?
これが この町のやり方ですの？
It's really harsh!
無茶苦茶ハードですよ
I told you the sheriff wasn't normal!
言ったでしょ
保安官は まともじゃないのよ
You!
（イングウェイ）お前ら
あっ ああ…
Don't bother.
（イングウェイ）もういいって
You could have slipped
the ropes at any time.
縄抜けなら
いつでもできたわけだ
Who the hell...
てめえ いったい何者…
（銃声）
（イングウェイ）お…
（荒くれ者Ａ）
オラア 強盗犯　頭出せ 頭！
Hey, robber man!
Stick your head out!
The pretty little head we've been given
official authorization to blow off!
（荒くれ者Ｂ）
お上公認で ぶっ飛ばせる
イカした頭をよお！
- What'll we do?
- What should we do?
どうしますの？
どうしよう？
C-C-Can I kill him?
（荒くれ者Ｃ）
こっ こ… こいつ
殺しちゃっていい？
（荒くれ者Ａ）
娘以外は好きにしな
You can kill anyone but the girl!
Neat!
（荒くれ者Ｃ）そうかあ
（執事）ヒッ ヒイ…
や… やめて
S-Stop! Don't kill me!
殺さないで
うわあああ
Sorry, I can't hear you
over all the gunfire!
（荒くれ者Ｃ）
銃声がすごくて聞こえましぇーん
ハハハハッ
あ？
（銃声）
（荒くれ者Ｃ）おお…
Has anyone ever told you
that you lack affection?
言われねえか？
慈愛の心が足りないって
（荒くれ者Ｃ）う…
な… 何やってる 撃て！
What're you doing?! Shoot him!
Do you think you have a hostage?!
（荒くれ者Ａ）
てめえ 人質を取ったつもりか！
撃てよ
Shoot him! Then we'll
have more to go around!
そうすりゃ 分け前が増える
（メリル）え…
Rem...
（ヴァッシュ）レム…
This guy's a fool!
こいつ バカだ！
Look out!!
（ミリィ）危なーい！
（荒くれ者Ｂ）うっ…
（荒くれ者Ｄ）ぐわっ
（荒くれ者Ｅ）うっ
（銃声）
うわあっ あたたた　おお！
（荒くれ者Ｃ）
えっ？ あっ え？
んー ぐぐぐ… だあっ
お…
What are you thinking?!
何 考えてやがる
どうして
撃たなかったんですの？
Why didn't you shoot him?
（ヴァッシュ）うーん
You didn't want to shoot him!
撃ちたくなかったんですよね
Well, you know...
I don't like pain.
だって 痛いのはイヤじゃん
ハア…
Never mind. Are you okay?
まあいい
大丈夫か
（デニム）うう…
Now do you see? The sheriff
never planned to give you the money!
これで分かったでしょ
保安官に お金を
渡すつもりなんてないのよ
I'll ask Daddy to let you go,
so stop this now!
パパに逃がしてもらうよう
頼んであげるから—
もうやめて
I can't do that.
そいつは できねえ
What?
えっ
There's a good reason I can't.
（イングウェイ）
できねえわけがあるんだよ
You know the huge graveyard
northeast of town?
町の北東に—
大きな墓地があるのを
知っているだろう
Our parents lie under that ground,
so barren even corpse weeds won't grow.
ムクロ草(そう)も生えねえ
荒れ地の下に—
俺たちの両親が眠ってる
All of my memories are of
them working, covered in dirt...
ホコリまみれで働いている
親父たちの姿しか覚えてねえが—
...but after 10 years,
they made this sandy soil arable.
10年掛けて
この砂地を使えるようにしたんだ
It was a huge accomplishment.
大したもんだよ
（発砲音）
（銃声）
But 15 years ago, the land
they had put everything into...
（イングウェイ）15年前だ
精根込めて耕した土地を—
...was stolen from them
by your father.
お前の親父が
横取りしやがったのさ
After "Grim Reaper" Bostalk
slaughtered them all!
死神ボストークが
農民を皆殺しにしてな！
You're lying!
ウソ…
What good would
lying do me now?
いまさら
ウソ言ってどうなる
I couldn't care less about
the money. Whatever happens...
カネなんて どうでもいい
どの道 逃げられやしねえ
だが—
...I won't run. But...
...I will take my revenge
for 15 years ago!
15年前の復讐(ふくしゅう)はさせてもらう
No matter what.
必ずだ！
You can't forget
something like that.
（ヴァッシュ）忘れる…
なんてできないよな
（荒くれ者たち）わあああ
（スタン）ああ？
（ボストーク）どうした？
What's happening?
なにっ！
What?!
Hang on.
We'll patch you up soon.
大丈夫か？
すぐ手当てしてやる
（ジーン）うっ うう…
（マーヴィン）
ああ… 俺は死ぬのか…
Am I gonna die?
Don't worry. The bullet went through,
and your pals are alive.
（ヴァッシュ）安心しな
弾(たま)は貫通してるし
仲間も生きてる
I will now relay the demands
of the criminals!
これから籠城犯からの
要求を伝える
（スタン）ん？
（風の音）
You're going?
（スタン）行くんですか？
He's named me and he has my daughter.
I can't refuse him.
（ボストーク）名指しの上
娘があれでは断れまい
But one thing, Stan...
だが スタン
貴様の責任は
あとで ゆっくり追求してやる
I'll make sure you're held
responsible for this later.
（スタン）フッ
He was feared as Bostalk
"The Grim Reaper" 18 years ago.
（スタン）死神ボストークと
恐れられたのは18年前
How the love of a daughter and
the passage of time can change a man!
娘かわいさか
年月(としつき)は人を変えるなあ
You have what you want.
Let the girl go.
（ヴァッシュ）もういいだろう
その娘(こ)を放してやってくれ
Forgive me.
（イングウェイ）すまなかったな
精算できない過去は
つらいものですわね
It's hard to have
a past you can't bury.
Don't look away.
目をそらすなよ
I know you're not foolish
enough to stay ignorant...
君の今までの人生が—
どんな人々の思いの上に
成り立っていたものか
...of the feelings of the people
your life was built on.
知らずにいられるほど
愚かでもないだろう
I know. I know!
分かってる　分かってるわ
But even if he did
these horrible things...
でもね
パパがひどいことを
してたとしても—
...to me, he's my daddy!
私には優しいパパなの
No matter how bad
or selfish I was...
どんなに反抗しても
わがまま言っても—
...to me, he was always
my daddy who loved me!
いつも優しく包んでくれた
パパなのよ
（銃声）
（ボストーク）うおお…
パパ！
Daddy!
Daddy, hold on!!
パパ しっかりして
Daddy! Daddy!
パパ　パパ！
I'm all right.
だ… 大丈夫だ
It's only my shoulder.
肩を撃たれただけだ
（ヴァッシュ）あ…
うう…
What are you crying about?
（イングウェイ）何 泣いてんだ？
Thank you!
ありがとう
You have no business thanking me.
お前に礼を言われる
筋合いはねえ
A distraction
threw my aim.
よけいなものを見ちまったから
手元が狂っただけだ
（ヴァッシュ）ううっ うう…
This weirdo is really crying!
（イングウェイ）
こいつ 本気で泣いてやがんのか？
フン 俺は自首するぜ
I'm turning myself in now.
Whoa, there. It's too
soon for the epilogue.
（スタン）おっと
エピローグには まだ早い
That's enough.
I'm through resisting.
やめろ もう抵抗はしねえ
まさか
してもらわないと困る
Don't say that.
I need you to resist.
なにっ？
What?
I never dreamed I'd be
given such an opportunity.
（スタン）
こんなに都合よく 事が運ぶとはな
"Trapped criminal kills Mr. Bostalk!"
籠城犯は
ボストーク伯爵を殺害
"Sheriff forced to shoot
bandit attempting resistance."
抵抗した犯人を止めるため—
保安官は やむなく
銃で射殺したと
It makes for a pretty article.
キレイな筋書きの
出来上がりとなるわけだ
Stan!
スタン
保安官という
役職でありながら—
You hold the position of sheriff!
How could you?!
なんてことを！
15 years ago, this man snatched
up all of the rights to this town.
15年前 この町の利権を
こいつが根こそぎ奪いやがった
And I rose no higher than sheriff.
そして俺は保安官 止まり
Don't you agree that it's my turn
to sip the sweet wine?
今度は俺が
甘い汁を吸う番だと思わないか
You were in on it, too?
じゃあ てめえも
- You scoundrel!
- You fiend!
この人でなし！
このろくでなし！
Throw down your weapons!
武器を捨ててもらおう
Lovely, like toothless stray dogs.
It feels grand to be superior!
（スタン）
いいねえ 丸腰の野良犬
全く 優位ってのは すばらしい
（メリル）ん？
ハッ
One question.
（ヴァッシュ）１つ質問
How does it feel to
kill passive human beings?
無抵抗な人間を殺すってのは
どんな気持ち？
Do you feel anything
when you burn your garbage?
貴様はゴミを燃やすときに—
何か感想をもつのか？
I see. Nifty answer.
なるほど イカす答えだ
はっ！
なぬっ！
（銃声）
な…なにっ
W-What?!
ふう…
Awesome, ma'am!
さすがは先輩
I'm amazed you
knew I was armed.
よく私が武器を持ってることが
分かりましたね
You helped me in
the bar, remember?
あのとき助けてくれたろ
（銃声）
I can recognize the smell of
gunpowder and grease instantly.
（ヴァッシュ）
火薬とグリースのにおいは
すぐ分かるんだ
Well, now...
さてと
You bastards!
き… 貴様ら
Hey, Sheriff! How does it feel
to be at the mercy of a stray dog?
どうだい？ 保安官
野良犬に命を
つかまれた気分は？
ぐっ… クソッ！
Dammit!
（銃声）
（スタン）ぐおお… がっ
ああ…
Relax, I won't kill you.
安心しな 殺しはしない
But, you...
だが あんたは…
（銃声）
...are unfit to be sheriff!
保安官 失格ですわ
ぐわわ…
I'll teach you
something useful, Sheriff!
（ヴァッシュ）
いいことを教えてあげよう 保安官
Repeat after me!
一緒に唱えるんだ！
（スタン）あ…　ああ
- This land...
- Th-This land...
この世は
こっ この世は…
...IS MADE OF...
...is made of?!
（ヴァッシュ）この世は！
（スタン）この世は！
...LOVE & PEACE!!
ラーブ＆ピースだ
♪〜
〜♪
When something is gained,
something is always lost.
（ヴァッシュ）
何かを得たとき
何かを失っていく
It's impossible to live
without facing that fact.
その事実に目を背けて
生き続けることはできない
What is lost will never return.
失ったものは元には戻らない
Important things.
Irreplaceable things.
大切なもの
かけがえのないもの
The things necessary
to protect those things.
それをなくさないために
必要なもの
The firm determination
packed into a bullet.
弾丸の中に込められた
揺るぎない決意
Man knows...
男は知っている
...knows that nothing will
begin unless he speaks.
黙っていては
何も始まらないことを
That nothing will change
unless he moves.
動きださないかぎり
変革が起きないことを